Guide to the Nicolai Berezowski Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Nicolai Berezowski Papers,
1817-1940
Berezowsky, Nicolai, 1900-1953
14 linear ft (ca. 4,000 items in 26 boxes & 4 volumes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079157
Biographical Note
Publisher, collector.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, financial records, photographs, drawings, engravings, and printed materials of Benjamin. The personal and business papers concern Benjamin's publishing and bookselling company, his numerous benefactions, the disposal of his collections, and many printed catalogs for his company, 1883-1940. The two major correspondents are the business and financial records for the printing, binding, and extensive promotion through a network of agents of Stedman's A LIBRARY OF AMERICAN LITERATURE FROM THE EARLIEST SETTLEMENT TO THE PRESENT TIME; new ed. (New York, W.E. Benjamin, 1894). There are also letters, manuscripts, documents, and drawings of English literary figures collected by Benjamin. Among these are six letters of George Eliot, 47 letters and six manuscripts of John Ruskin, and three letters and one manuscript of Joseph Mallord Turner, with four letters relating to the artist. In addition there ten drawings and watercolors by Ruskin.
Also, 37 letters and one manuscript were removed from Benjamin's copy of Robert Langton's THE CHILDHOOD AND YOUTH OF CHARLES DICKENS and cataloged for this collection. One letter from Langton and 32 from others were addressed to Charles Roach Smith, a well-known antiquary of London. Several letters are concerned with numismatics (including two from John Stuart, Earl of Darnley, one each from William Henry Ashe, baron Heytesbury, and Chase Spence), but most of these letters relate to Charles Dickens: three letters from his son, Sir Henry Fielding Dickens, six from Henry Gardiner Adams, of the Mechanics' Institute of Chatham and Rochester, one each from Frederick William Fairholt, and Charles Stewart Montgomerie Lockhart, manuscript notes by John Gough Nichols, a letter from John Bowen Rowlands, one each from W.J. Taylor and Joseph Cotton Wigram, Bishop of Rochester, two from Humphrey Wood of the Mechanics' Institute, and of particular interest the two letters from Sampson Seaton, whose father was a friend of the father of the famous novelist. Many of these letters were written at the time of Dickens' death from people living in the area of Rochester and Chatham, his early childhood homes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 5 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Subject Files
Series III: Photographs
Series IV: Clippings
Series V: Scores
Subjects
Mechanics' Institute of Chatham and Rochester.; Phelps, Charles Henry.; Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1833-1908.; Eliot, George, 1819-1880.; Ruskin, John, 1819-1900.; Turner, J. M. W. (Joseph Mallord William), 1775-1851.; Langton, Robert.; Smith, Charles Roach, 1807-1890.; Darnley, John Stuart,--Earl of.; Ashe, William Henry.; Heytesbury,--Baron.; Spence, Chase.; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870.; Dickens, Henry Fielding,--Sir.; Adams, Henry Gardiner.; Fairholt, F. W. (Frederick William), 1814-1866.; Lockhart, C. S. M. (Charles Stewart Montgomerie); Nichols, John Gough.; Rowlands, John Bowen.; Taylor, W. J.; Wigram, Joseph Cotton.; Wood, Humphrey.; Seaton, Sampson.; Publishers and publishing--New York (State)--New York.; Booksellers and bookselling--New York (State)--New York.; Authors, English.; Numismatics.; Paintings.; Photoprints.; Engravings.; Drawings.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1943 M-43 Cartwright, Beatrice Benjamin and Henry Rogers Benjamin Gift
Alternate Formats
Royal Cortissoz and John Ruskin letters are on microfilm.
Gift of Beatrice Benjamin Cartwright & Henry Rogers Benjamin, 1943.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Adler, F. Charles, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Allgemeiner Deutscher Musikverein, 1931 (Box 1)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1949 (Box 1)
  - American Composers' Alliance, 1940-1945 (Box 1)
  - American Library in Paris, 1947 (Box 1)
  - American Music Center, 1947 (Box 1)
  - American Music Rental Library, 1940 (Box 1)
  - American Musicological Society, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Ames, Elizabeth, 1932-1936 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Dwight, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Phyllis, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Beth (Mrs. C.), 1953 (Box 1)
  - Antognini, Cirillo, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Antik, Anna, 1940-1953 (Box 1)
  - Antonini, Alfredo, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Appel, Richard G. 1931-1934 (Box 1)
  - Associated Music Publishers, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Autori, Franco, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Aylesworth, Merlin Hall, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Babin, Victor, 194l (Box 1)
  - Baden-Baden Generalmusikdirektor, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Bailly, Louis, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Bakaleinikoff, Vladimir, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Balaban, Emanuel, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Barbirolli, John, 1938-1940 (Box 1)
  - Barrére, Georges, 1932-1936 (Box 1)
  - Barzin, Leon, 1932-1952 (Box 1)
  - Bastow, Robert D. 1936 (Box 1)
  - Bean, Betty Randolph, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Bechert, Paul, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Beebe, Carolyn, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Bender, Albert M. 1940 (Box 1)
  - Berezowsky, Alice (Mrs. Nicolai T.), n.d. and 1946 (Box 1)
  - Berezowsky, Judith (Mrs. Nicolai), 1951-1953 (Box 1)
  - Berezowsky, Nicolai Letters to Berezowsky, 1932-1936; Fan mail to Berezowsky, 1936-1948, 1922-1953 (Box 1)
  - Bierman, William, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Birchard, C. C. & Co. 1935-1937 (Box 1)
  - Bohemians, The, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Boosey & Hawkes, 1948-1953 (Box 1)
  - Borowski, Feli, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1931-1941 (Box 1)
  - Bottenhein, Salomon, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Boulanger, Nadia, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Bowdoin College, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Brunswick, Mark, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Burgin, Richard, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Burkat, Leonard, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Byman, Barnett, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Campione, A. Peter. 1949 (Box 2)
  - Canavan, M. J. 1953 (Box 2)
  - Carlton, Joseph R. 1951 (Box 2)
  - Carter, Elliott, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Chapman, R. E. 1950 (Box 2)
  - Casella, Alfredo, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Cheney, Gwen, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Chester, J & W., Ltd, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Clarke, Stanley, 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Cleghorn, James, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Cleveland Public Library, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Clifton, Chalmers, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Charles, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Columbia University, 1952-1948 (Box 2)
  - Committee on International Echange of Persons, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Composers-Authors Guild, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Cone, Edward T. 1941-1951 (Box 2)
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1927-1940 (Box 2)
  - Copeland, H. W. 1950 (Box 2)
  - Copland, Aaron, n.d. and 1937 (Box 2)
  - Corcoran, James B. 1948 (Box 2)
  - Cowell, Henry, 1933-1942 (Box 2)
  - Creston, Paul, 1936-1938 (Box 2)
  - Cuvelier, Marcel, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Daniel, Ange, 1947 (Box 2)
  - de Filippi, Amedeo, 1935-1947 (Box 2)
  - Deming, Howard F. 1953 (Box 2)
  - Denver Symphony Orchestra, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Deutscher Tonsetzer, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Deter, Graham C. 1940 (Box 2)
  - Diamond, David, 1935-1952 (Box 2)
  - Dickinson, Thomas H. 1936 (Box 2)
  - Dickson, John, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Dobrowny, Issay, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Donovan, Richard, 1937-1940 (Box 2)
  - Downes, Olin, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Duke, John, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Dukelsky, Vladimir, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Edward MacDowell Association, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Ehrich, Edward Price, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Elkan, Henri, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Engel, Carl, 1926-1938 (Box 2)
  - Engel, Lehman, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Engles, George, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Etler, Alvin, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Ewen, David, 1934-1945 (Box 3)
  - Ezerman., Sophia (Mrs. D. Hendrick), 1937 (Box 3)
  - Farrar, F. N. 1952 (Box 3)
  - Fassett, James H. 1946-1947 (Box 3)
  - Faulkner, Maurice, 1939-1945 (Box 3)
  - Fiedler, Arthur, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Finney, Ross Lee, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Fiorillo, Dante, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Fitelberg, Jerzy, 1937-1950 (Box 3)
  - Flesch, Carl, 1929-1936 (Box 3)
  - Fletcher, Stanley, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Frankenstein, Alfred V. 1942 (Box 3)
  - Freiberg, Stella H. (Mrs. J. Walter), 1936 (Box 3)
  - Friedenberg, Muriel, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Frosch, Aaron R. 1952 (Box 3)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Galay Music Corporation, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Gannon, Theo F. 1937 (Box 3)
  - Gantzoff, Feodor, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Gatti, Guido M. 1945 (Box 3)
  - Gèraldy, Paul (?), 1948 (Box 3)
  - Gerzenstein, Tatiana Smirnov de, 1932 - 1951 (Box 3)
  - Gladstone, T. E. 1950 (Box 3)
  - Glanville-Hicks, Peggy, n.d (Box 3)
  - Goldman, Richard Franco, 1943-1952 (Box 3)
  - Goldmark, Rubin, 1928-1939 (Box 3)
  - Goldofsky, Boris, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Golschmann, Vladimir, 1936-1939 (Box 3)
  - Goosens, Eugene, 1930-1941 (Box 3)
  - Gordon, Jacques, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Gorton, Ronald W. 1951 (Box 3)
  - Grant, Margaret, 1941-1052 (Box 3)
  - Grechaninov, Aleander, 1927 - 1947 (Box 3)
  - Groner, Powell, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Gruenberg, Louis, 1927-1935 (Box 3)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Haensel & Jones, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Hageman, Eleanore (Mrs. Richard), 1947 (Box 3)
  - Hageman, Richard, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Hale, Philip, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Hallowell, Margaret B. n.d. (Box 3)
  - Hanson, Howard, 1939-1945 (Box 3)
  - Harrington, 1933? (Box 3)
  - Harris, Roy, 1937-1945 (Box 3)
  - Harrison, Guy Fraser, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Haymanns Verlag (Carl), 1934 (Box 3)
  - Heineman, Marianne F, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Heinsheimer, Hans, 1938-1941 (Box 3)
  - Heinsheimer, Norbert, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Herbert, Walter, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Hershberger, John, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Heyward, Dorothy, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Hijman, Julius, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Edward Burlingame, 1936-1946 (Box 3)
  - Hoade, Martin, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Holden, Sally Hay, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Holtzscheiter, Ina, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Howe, Mary, 1937-1940 (Box 3)
  - Hudson, H. Lewis, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Hughes, Langston, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Hutcheson, Ernest, 1929-1940 (Box 3)
  - Independent Music Publishers, 1944 (Box 4)
  - International Society for Contemporary Music, 1941-1950 (Box 4)
  - Ippòlito, Carmèla, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Iturbi, Josè 1935 - 1936 (Box 4)
  - Jacobi, Frederick, 1939-1950 (Box 4)
  - James, Philip, 1940-1951 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Thor, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Jonckeere, M. 1931-1932 (Box 4)
  - Josten, Werner, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Judd, George E. 1938 (Box 4)
  - Judson, Arthur, 1929-1934 (Box 4)
  - Judson Concert Management, 1934-1938 (Box 4)
  - Juilliard Musical Foundation, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Juilliard School of Music, 1933-1938 (Box 4)
  - Katz, Alfred, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Kay, Lisan, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Kaycoff, Evelyn, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Keats, Sheila, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Keeney, Wendell, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Kelberine, Alearder, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Kerr, Harrison, 1940-1945 (Box 4)
  - Keysser, Friedrich, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Kindler, Hans, 1936-1938 (Box 4)
  - Kirkpatrick, Ralph, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kohn, Walter T. 1928 (Box 4)
  - Kolar, Victor, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Konratev, Nicolai, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kostelanetz, André 1941-1949 (Box 4)
  - Koussevitsky, Natalia, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Koussevitsky, Olga, 1931-1941 (Box 4)
  - Koussevitsky, Serge, 1932-1952 (Box 4)
  - Krasner, Louis, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Kroll, William, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kurenko, Maria, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Kurzmann, Theo and Rita, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Laberge, Bernard, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Laidlaw, Robert, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Landers, Arthur, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
  - Lange, Hans, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Langton, Stephen, 1951 (Box 4)
  - La Prade, Ernest, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Laurent, Mme. Henri, 1945 (Box 4)
  - League of Composers, 1947-1952 (Box 4)
  - Lederman, Minna, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Lessard, John, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Barbara, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Lichstein, Arthur, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Lipner, J. 1935 (Box 4)
  - Lippincott Co. 1945 (Box 4)
  - Lopatnikoff, Nikolai, 1926-1953 (Box 4)
  - Lopatnikoff, Nora, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
  - Lopatnikoff, Sally, 1951 (Box 5)
  - Louchheim, Catherine (Mrs. Walter Clinton), n.d. (Box 5)
  - Louchheim, Walter Clinton, 1940-1950 (Box 5)
  - Lourié, Arthur, 1941 - 1952 (Box 5)
  - Lowman, Lawrence W. 1931-1953 (Box 5)
  - McDonald, Harl, 1940-1943 (Box 5)
  - MacDowell, Marion (Mrs. Edward), 1951-1952 (Box 5)
  - McFarland, Frances, 1937 (Box 5)
  - McGavack, Thomas H. 1953 (Box 5)
  - McGill, Wallace R. 1932 (Box 5)
  - Mahler, Fritz, 1940-1941 (Box 5)
  - Maier, Guy, 1936-1937 (Box 5)
  - Maikoff, A. 1936 (Box 5)
  - Malcolm, Scott, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Marks Music Corp. 1950 (Box 5)
  - Marquis Publishing Co. 1942 (Box 5)
  - Mayer, Corinne, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Mazzeo, Rosario, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Mengelberg, Willem, 1928-1935 (Box 5)
  - Merovitch, Aleander, 1932 (Box 5)
  - Meyer, Abe, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Mills, E. C. 1932 (Box 5)
  - Mills Music Publishers, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Miquelle, Renée, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Mitropolous, Dimitri, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Moldavan, Nicolas, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Moore, Douglas, 1940-1948 (Box 5)
  - Moore, Emily, 1923-1941 (Box 5)
  - Morris, Harold, 1934-1938 (Box 5)
  - Morris, Willavene, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Moscow First Symphony Ensemble, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Music Guild (Chicago), 1939 (Box 5)
  - Naginski, Charles, n.d. (Box 5)
  - National Orchestral Association, 1942 (Box 5)
  - National Society of Music and Art, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Nelson, Boris Erich, 1947-1951 (Box 5)
  - Newman, Jacob Kieferman, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Newman, Mae Pollak, 1929 (Box 5)
  - Newman, Melvin S. 1943 (Box 5)
  - Newman, Saunders & Co., Inc. 1930 (Box 5)
  - New York Public Library, 1931-1940 (Box 5)
  - Nissim, Rudolf, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Nordoff, Paul, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - O'Connell, Charles, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Onnou, Alphonse, 1917 (Box 5)
  - Ormandy, Eugene, 1932-1951 (Box 6)
  - Ornstein, Leo, 1933-1935 (Box 6)
  - Ortega, Ricardo, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Ouglitzky, Paul Pecheniha, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
  - Paitchadze, G. 1931-1937 (Box 6)
  - Pasternak, L. 1931-1934 (Box 6)
  - Pattison, Lee, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Pavlova, Nina Grigorevna, 1936 (Box 6)
  - Persichetti, Vincent, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Pettis, Ashley, 1935-1938 (Box 6)
  - Peyser, Herbert F. n.d. (Box 6)
  - Philadelphia Free Library, 1937-1952 (Box 6)
  - Philips, Edna, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Piatigorsky, Gregor, 1927-1940 (Box 6)
  - Polah, Andre, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
  - Polk, Rudolph, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Pollak, Robert, 1928-1953 (Box 6)
  - Pons, Lily, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Pravosudovich, Natalie, 1931-1936 (Box 6)
  - Putterman, David J. 1945-1952 (Box 6)
  - Rabinovich, Yasha I. 1931-1934 (Box 6)
  - Raichle, Frank G, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Random House, 1951-1953 (Box 6)
  - Reichamusikkamer, n.d (Box 6)
  - Reiner, Fritz, 1931-1940 (Box 6)
  - Reis, Claire R. 1931-1949 (Box 6)
  - Rhodes, Willard, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Riegger, Wallingford, 1937-1949 (Box 6)
  - Robbins Music Corp. 1940 (Box 6)
  - Robinson, Geroid T. 1953 (Box 6)
  - Rodzinski., Artur, 1932-1944 (Box 6)
  - Rogers, Bernard, 1935 (Box 6)
  - Root, L. Carroll, 1935 (Box 6)
  - Rosen, Lucie Bigelow, 1936-1949 (Box 6)
  - Rosen, Walter T. 1950 (Box 6)
  - Rosenbach, A. S. W. 1933 (Box 6)
  - Rosenbaum, Samuel R. 1943-1947 (Box 6)
  - Ross, S. L. 1922 (Box 6)
  - Rubstein, Ariel, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Sakouta, Vitaly, 1935-1936 (Box 6)
  - Salvation Army, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Salzedo, Carlos, 1935 (Box 6)
  - San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Schirmer Music Publishers, 1927 (Box 6)
  - Schloss, Oscar, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Schneider, Mischa, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Schulhof, Andrew, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Schuman, William, 1938-1947 (Box 6)
  - Schuster, Joseph, 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - Schwartz, Paul E, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Schwieger, Hans, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Scott, Joan (Mrs. Paul), n.d. (Box 6)
  - Seebachs, Julius F. 1935-1939 (Box 7)
  - Seligman, Selig, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Sessions, Roger, 1934-1944 (Box 7)
  - Sevitzky, Fabien, 1951-1953 (Box 7)
  - Shively, Barbara Frist, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Shoobe, Lou, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Siegmeister, Elie, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Sigma Alpha Iota, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Siloti, Aleander, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Skavenna, Aleander, 1932 (Box 7)
  - Slonimskii, Nicolas, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Smallens, Aleander, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Carleton Sprague, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Smith, David Stanley, 1938 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Moses, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Speller, R. E. B. 1941 (Box 7)
  - Spivacke, Harold, 1937-1953 (Box 7)
  - Sproul, Harold, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Stadium Concerts, Inc. 1925 (Box 7)
  - Stagma, 1934-1937 (Box 7)
  - Stassévitch, Paul, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Stegmann, G. F. 1951 (Box 7)
  - Steinberg, William, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Stern, I. A. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Stewart, Reginald, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Stock, Frederick, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Stoessel, Albert, 1932-1941 (Box 7)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1931-1952 (Box 7)
  - Stokowski, Olga Samaroff, 1929-1932 (Box 7)
  - Stringfield, Lamar, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Stroock, Sol M. 1933 (Box 7)
  - Strunk, Oliver, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
  - Szigeti, Joseph, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Taylor, Davidson, 1936-1943 (Box 7)
  - Taylor, Deems, 1945-1947 (Box 7)
  - Taylor, Harold, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Tcherepnin, Aleander, 1930-1935 (Box 7)
  - Thalheimer, Elsa, 1931 (Box 7)
  - Thompson, Randall, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Thompson, Stuart M. 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - Thomson., Virgil, 1944 (Box 7)
  - Tillotson, Frederick, 1944 (Box 7)
  - Tipton, W. S. 1934 (Box 7)
  - Tolstoy, Aleandra, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Tyler, A. Ranger, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Ullman, Richard H. 1950 (Box 7)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1926 (Box 7)
  - Van Praag, Maurice, 1926 (Box 7)
  - Vogel, A. 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - VyruBoxv, A. 1929-1932 (Box 7)
  - Wallenstein, Alfred, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Walter, Bruno, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Waters, Edward N. 1940 (Box 7)
  - Waman, Franz, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Weaner, Mawell, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Weiss, Adolph, 1941-1950 (Box 7)
  - Weissberger, L. Arnold, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Weissel, William L. 1953 (Box 7)
  - Werner, Jules, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Wertz, Guy W. 1946 (Box 7)
  - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Whittail, Mrs. Matthew John, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Wicker, Frances G. 1947 (Box 7)
  - Willson, Meredith, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Winston, Elizabeth, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Woempner, Henry, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Wolfsohn Musical Bureau, 1926 (Box 7)
  - Wood, Audrey, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Worms, Alice, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Worms, Margaret B. 1928 (Box 7)
  - Yaddo Music Festival, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Zimmerman, Dr. Louis, 1931 (Box 7)
  - Zirato, Bruno, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Letters in chronological order, 1926-1947 (Box 7, Folder 164)
- Series II: Subject Files
  - Address Lists; American Composers' Alliance; American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom; American Society of Composers Authors and Publishers; Biographical; Birchard and Company royalty statement, 1923-1944 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - File 1); CBS and NBC Broadcasts (1926-1944); File 2); Contracts (1923-1940); Coolidge Spring Quartet itineraries; File 3); Koussevitzky; Kurenko, Maria; League of Composers (1940-1951); Notes; Pollak, Robert; Royalties, receipts; File 4); Societies; Sprague-Coleman; Steinway; WPA/Federal Music Project (1936-1938); Worms, Margaret; Yaddo Music Festival, 1923-1944 (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
- Series III: Photographs
  Includes professional photographs of Berezowsky with violin and snapshots of the Coolidge Quartet trip to Honolulu in 1939.
  - File 5) 21 photographs and 1 pencil drawing of Nicolai Berezowsky; File 6) 68 photographs of Berezowsky, family and friends, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- Series IV: Clippings
  - Clippings on performances and works, 1937-1953 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
- Series V: Scores
  - Suite for flute, oboe, etc., op. 11; Symphony #1, op. 12, 1931; Quartet, op. 16; Sinfonietta, op. 17; Symphony #2, op. 18, 1934; Sextet #2, op. 20; Quintet #2, op. 22; String quartet with orchestra, op. 23 (Box 1215-1, Folder 1-10)
  - Brass Suite IV, op. 24, 1942; Sextet concerto for string orchestra, op. 26; Symphony #4, op. 27, 1943; Bowdoin Hymn, June 1944; Concerto, op. 31, 1944; Babar the Elephant, op. 40, 1953; Unidentified scores, 1942-1953 (Box 1215-2, Folder 1-10)